Finding Aid for Grace Church (Mount Clemens, Mich.) records, 1871-1971
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Grace Church (Mount Clemens, Mich.) records 1871-1971
Grace Church (Mount Clemens, Mich.)
1 linear foot
86967 Ba 2
Mount Clemens, Michigan, Episcopal Church; minutes of the vestry and of St. Anne’s Guild, and other records.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was deposited by the church (donor no. 6636 ) in 1981.
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The record group is open to research.
Grace Church was organized by a missionary priest, the Rev. Edward Magee, in the fall of 1849. An application for admittance into union with the Diocese of Michigan was approved at the Diocesan Convention of 1850. Despite early struggles to stay together, interest in establishing an active Episcopal parish grew with the close of the Civil War. On September 6, 1870, the cornerstone for a permanent home for Grace Church was laid. Though there was some growth, the church needed help from the Missionary Fund of the Diocese to keep going. Despite these struggles, on April 29, 1892, the mortgage for the church building was discharged, and on June 23, Bishop Davies consecrated Grace Church. By 1894, the congregation felt sufficiently prosperous to build a Rectory "complete with outbuildings and walks."
In the Twentieth Century, Grace Church became an influential force for outreach in the Mt. Clemens community with a membership roll in the 1990s of 150 families.
The record group is arranged into a single series of Church Records. Included are vestry minutes, minutes of St. Anne's Guild, treasurer's record books, record book of the Women's Guild, and church newsletters.
Subjects:
Episcopal Church--Michigan--Mount Clemens.; Mount Clemens (Mich.); Grace Church (Mount Clemens, Mich.)
- Church records
  - Vestry minutes, 1871-1922 (Box 1)
    - 1871-1898 (Box 1)
    - 1899-1913 (Box 1)
    - 1913-1922 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of St. Anne's Guild, 1912-1933
    - 1912-1918 (Box 1)
    - 1925-1929 (Box 1)
    - 1930-1933 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's book, 1878-1888 (Box 1)
    - 1878-1888 (Box 1)
    - 1891-1898 (Box 1)
  - Women's Guild Record book, 1926-1933 (Box 1)
  - Church newsletter (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)